Hi,my nameis Sri Kumar and
it's my final capstone project named
Capstone IQ. So essentially what it is,
it's valuation engine that is also mixed
with the sentiment analyzer. And then for
the third part, which is kind of creative
part, you have a stress tester based on
those results. So first, if you look at
this page, this is the dashboard. So the
opening of the website, it's basically a
macro dashboard of. The overview of what
we're going to look at in the website, it
tells you what we have. We have the
valuation engine makes for the sentiment
analysis and evaluation engine tab, and
then we have the scenario test stress
tester based on those results and the
stress tester tab. It's one thing to note
that this was made with AI Disclosure and
it also uses the driver plugin and uses
LLN APIs from Anthropic Cloud and News.
Versus, um, so yeah, so before we get
into the launch pipeline, I'm kind of
kind of going to talk to you about how
this process should be used. So one big
limitation of this process is that the
data quality model assumptions and
compounding errors go across components.
So essentially if there's one error in
the thing, it'll completely flow down and
the errors come from the API. So if your
API key isn't fully. And their results
you're getting aren't like fully there.
The math won't workout. So you have to
make sure the data quality is good for
the whole start of it. And I'll talk more
about the limitations as we get through
part by part. So the platform also uses
simulated inputs. So the end heuristics
are not representative of the total
analysis. Yes, there are some assumptions
you have to make, and we're going to talk
through the numbers that we make with
those assumptions. But that is a
limitation. This system, you do have to
make assumptions. It's not a completely
predictive model. So with that being
said, I'm kind of going to click this
launch pipeline button and it'll take us
to this valuation engine. I already have
my API key put in. You're going to need
an Anthropic API key, but I'm going to
just put in the Apple stock ticker. Any
stock ticker will work. I'll use Apple.
It's a mature company, mature companies.
Likely give you a lot of results for
online information. So as you see the
sentiment signals, we get a lot of
results because it is an online company.
So at the top I'm just going to walk you
through everything we have the Apple the
the ticket for it is APL. It gives you
what type of industry it's in. It's in
the technology and consumer electronics
industry and this current share price for
it as training. 19811 per share price.
Then we're going to go into Section 1.
Section 1 is the sentiment signals. So
here you see the three different places
online where you can get your data from.
We chose Reddit X and financial journals.
The financial journals are Wall Street
journals, Bloomberg and Forbes I believe,
and the reason we chose those is simply
because there was an API. Me from a
program called news source for it and
other sources weren't in those new
sources. It's a similar reason why we
chose accent Reddit. It's because I found
an API key for it. You can easily apply
your own API key. You get more sources in
here If you find a site that I'll give it
to you. But for this we did Reddit X and
financial journals as mentioned there. So
all of those are kind of. Added up to get
to what we see on the left is this
sentiment score. So the way it works is
it tracks the headlines of the news
articles that come out on Reddit relating
to Apple. So for example, if there's a
Reddit post saying ohh, Apple stocks are
shockingly decreasing, then the sentiment
for that will be marked as a negative on
a scale of -1 to 1 and it compounds. All
18,200 of them to get an overall view of
how the public views these stocks. So one
downside to this is there can be false
positive and false negatives if if an
answer is shocking, shocking is a word
that's perceived negative by the AI,
right? But shocking can be a good thing.
So the AI doesn't know how to distinguish
between tone. So you do get some false
positives and you do get. And false
negatives. So you really have to choose
what sources you analyze more carefully.
So here is where I'm going to talk about
how you can actually edit the weighting
of this. So in my opinion, sources like
financial journals of Wall Street Journal
and Bloomberg are less likely to use
coded language that is really, really
reactive because while their new sources
that someone verifying it's they have to
remain more objective. With stuff like
Reddit and X are independent researchers
so while you get the data quicker,
there's not a lot of like accuracy to it
because anyone can post anything. So as a
result I want to wait X and Twitter a lot
less. I'm just going
to click on 10% for each. So that's his
10 and that's it. It's 8 and 11%. I
misclicked. I don't have my mouse on me,
but it's going to be 8 and 11%. That's
what we're going to use. I think X is a
little bit more reliable than Reddit
because, well, X does have those
community notes that you can see and
it'll tell you if there's any information
that's blatantly wrong. This Reddit
doesn't really have that. So as you saw,
the public sentiment score dropped from
point 642.59 because we waited financial
journals more. And as
a result, that .58 went up and now it's
getting weighted as more. And so the .65
from the Twitter, which was the highest
segment is now weighted as less. So your
overall public sentiment score will
decrease. Apples are pretty mature
companies, so there's not a lot of like
bad reputations for it. So we'll go with
this .59 estimated. Well, we're also in
an AI tech boom. There's a lot of AI
integration into stuff. So it's a pretty
good estimate to say that these tech
companies will be going up in the long
term. So next we get to the next step,
which is the integration engine. And this
integration engine actually does change
with the public sentiment score and you
can modify it over here. So if you were
looking earlier, these results changed.
So now we have to make. Our base GCF
assumption, so this is one of the
limitations that I referenced earlier.
You do have to make assumptions for these
companies because well, you, you do have
to assume something if you're trying to
make a predictive model. So for our case,
we have the three assumptions that we can
make. We can change these numbers
wherever, but it's your base weighted
average cost of capital, your base growth
and your terminal growth. So for the
numbers that we're going to use. So the
base weighted average cost of capital,
we're going to choose 8 to 9%. We'll find
the middle ground of 8.5%. Why are we
picking this? Because well, there's a
load of debt to equity ratio for Apple
because it's a pretty mature industry.
And when you're taking on less debt and
you're more equity driven than your
overall weighted average cost of capital
is going to be lower if you look at.
Similar mature industries, it'll say that
they range from the range of 8 to 9%.
We chose the middle ground of 8.5%.
Again, for mature industries, you want to
go from 8 to 9 and for faster growing
in like preceding revenue companies, you
want to go to say 9 to 15%. It
also matters about the saturation of the
market. I would say the tech. Market is
pretty saturated and companies for focus
more on long term growth, so they don't
take on as much debt. So the 8 to 9%
assumption is perfect. And then for base
growth, you want to go for between 7 and
9% for similar reasons. So we'll go for
7%. We're going to go on to the lower end
again, mature companies don't focus on
short term growth growth as much and they
focus on making profits. Shareholder over
long term values, so because you're
looking at that you want to estimate a
lower growth rate because they're not as
focused with scaling upward and they're
more focused with consistent growth. And
then the final one that you want to look
at is terminal growth rate. For terminal
growth rate, we're going to set it as 2%
because 2% is what the market appreciate
that over the long term and no matter how
mature or. Fast growing your industry is
over a 10 year. You'll never beat the
market. So 2% is the perfect amount
because we're going to say it scales with
the economy and then we're going to go
and we can edit our sentiment impact. So
if you've been looking the effective
weighted average cost of capital, the
effective growth and terminal growth have
all been changing. So if I change it to
3.5, you saw all those numbers trickled
down completely, you saw the intrinsic
value per share. The equity value of the
enterprise value change. So I'm going to
set it back over to 2%, which is the
number we set at. And you see all those
numbers readjusting. So then we can look
at a sentiment impact. So this is
essentially putting how much weighting we
have on the sentiment score. For the sake
of this, I'm going to say we're going to
put a 35% estimate because I think
companies like Apple. Which are mature
are a lot less reactive to public
sentiment because they're they're pretty
safe, they're in a lot of ETF. So you
know that you're focused on long term
growth rate and not effective changing.
So we don't need to estimate that the
sentiment is going to change the value of
the stock too much. So we're going to
keep it at 35% because it still does
affect it, but it doesn't affect as much
as if it was a preceded company. So
now we see that the effective weighted
average cost craft growth, internal
growth have changed and below here we
tells you the adjustments. So for for all
the assumptions that we made, it's a -,
8.41 is absent for effective growth at
the plus 8.62 and for terminal growth is
a + 8.21 and then you get these weighted
average cost of capital growth and
terminal growth. From your sentiment
analyzer and your integrated engine, and
these are the values that are actually
pitched into the how the whole thing
works. So then it trickles down into this
valuation output. So as you've seen, it's
a pretty steadily stream. Your inputs
from public sentiment are put into the
integration engine and those inputs then
trickle down to the valuation output is
what we kind of look at these. You know
product. So you see in this black box, it
kind of shows you all the numbers that we
really need. It tells you the present
value, your financial cash flows, your
terminal value and it calculates that
into your enterprise value, your equity
value and everything that's displayed
down there. These numbers are just
calculated with the the normal present
value formulas for financial cash flows
for terminal. Value it just all
automatically calculating that off the
assumptions that we have up here. So then
you get your final results, right. So it
tells you that it's trading at $155.45
per share and that's your intrinsic value
per share. And it also tells you your
enterprise value. That's the total of
financial cash flows and terminal value
and it tells you the equity value which
is your. TV of plus cash minus debt
essentially like how much total money
you're actually taking on so all of this
tells you like how the sentiment of the
public and what assumptions you're making
actually shows you the difference between
the true value of the stock and stock
that you're buying right now so Apple is
actually had $198 right now but your true
value because. Public sentiment on it is
like due to an AI tech boom and we're
saying that that's going to fizzle out in
the short term. So our terminal growth
rate is low is we actually only predict
it to be $155 of value right now. And
this is kind of displayed if you want a
whole table and there's 2D sentiment
analysis, sensitivity analysis where. It
plots weighted average cost of capital by
growth. So you can look at a range of
weighted average cost of capital of ±2
and a growth range of ±2, two. So right
now we're looking at 8.1 and 7.6. That's
how we get the $155. But it gives you the
entire range. And this is kind of shown
that shows you like how much can you
actually value your?Company because if
you look at it over here, you see that
there's really only like really bullish
stuff that your company is positive in.
But the majority of cases, safe cases, we
would say from 7.1% to 10.1% in your
weighted average cost of capital, which
is what you would consider a normal
market or a recession market. You see
that you're actually read all over, which
means you can kind of make these
assumptions. This is not the best stock
to invest in, and we did that by
compiling both the sentiment signal and
the valuation outputs. Then you can look
at all of those results in this AI stress
tester. So again, it's going to have to
load everything back up out here. It's
going to take a few seconds. It's just
taking all the data. From those, yeah,
and it's giving you the base case, the AI
tech broom, macro recession, high
inflation stock to get through the
intrinsic value of the stock. So right
now we're looking at the base case of
Apple. So these are all the inputs that
we got last time. So our stress whack is
0.1%, strength grows 0.1%, and stress
sentiment is 0.62%. All these were
calculated in the valuation engine. Have
when you change those results, these
results will change. Now we can look at
the different cases. So the way away we
assumed tech boom, macro recession, high
inflation shock, and there's a boom. You
assume the markets going up. So it's +6
on your plus .6 on your estimate -1.5
billion you're stressed wash and plus 3%
on your stress growth. These are all just
market averages. I looked up tech market
average growth for sentiments, stressed
walk, and stress growth for each of the
three sectors. I just took the results
off of local. You can also edit these as
you would want in the code. Same with
macro recession. It's -0.8% + 2.5% -, 4%.
Again, these are just numbers that were
out there. I think it was Forbes that I
looked up and these were the numbers that
they gave you. And then you have all
those for the high inflation stock as
well, right? And so essentially this guy
that gives you the margin of safety on
what you're actually betting on when you
invest in a stock. So if we assume the
boom like we are right now, we see our
intrinsic value is 202.85. And that's
actually pretty bad value because even in
the boom, absolutely massive boom, you're
only going to be trading this. Back at
$4.00 over what it is right now, you're
assuming best case scenario, we only see
it's $4.00 value based off of the public
sentiment and the valuation engine with
the inputs that we made earlier.
Similarly for macro recession, you see
that your intrinsic value is like really,
really bad. You're going to be losing a
lot of money long term in this high
inflation shock. You're going to be
losing 777. Dollars per share, the only
one that was kind of good in a recession,
mature stocks are the one that thrives.
So that's why you saw Apple was doing
pretty good there. But you see there's no
reason real reason to trade into
something like Apple according to this,
because despite the sentiment being good,
you're really just investing in something
super long term because it won't ever
like bounce up in the short term because
it's a mature industry. So now I'm going
to head back over to the. Valuation
engine and talked about like some
application of this. So I believe I've
walked through the tickers and I've
already talked about the limitations of
this. So now let's talk about how a
professional would use something like
this using something like Apple. They
would use this to essentially make a high
and low of the market. So maybe, maybe we
only want to go off of what X says. So
we get this 0.63 number where we value X
super highly and X is telling me that
it's going to go up a lot. So a
professional would then look at this and
say, ohh, my, maybe I'll put my base wack
at 7% because I don't need to take on or
10 percent, 10 to 7% because we're going
to take on more debt because we want to
aggressively go right now. Our brains
growth rate is going to be higher in our
terminal growth rate is going to be
higher. And now you actually see all
these numbers are going up a lot. And
it's telling you that even in a best case
scenario where you assume that Apple is
going for absolute growth, your intrinsic
value for share is pretty low. And if you
remembered earlier, I showed you the
example of what if we assumed Apple is
going to go with this mature strategy
that they've been going over for the past
20 years and we saw that the intrinsic
value per share was down there. So this
kind of shows the example of how an
industry professional can use it. They
can create the low end of the segment,
the high end of segment and just using
the assumption of how the market will
grow based off of other factors that they
know because they're an industry
professional, they can see whether or not
you would actually want to buy this stock
for long term value. So that's
pretty much how the whole thing works.
Um, it's an integrated system. Again, I'm
just going to recap it. So using these
sentiment signals, you see that all the
values change whenever you change
anything in here. Same with the beta base
whack your sentiment impact when you
change all of these, it's trickles down
through the entire program and it changes
all your. Values. So that's the big
limitation that we've talked about is
that if you got one thing wrong with your
whack, if your assumption is wrong, then
all of your future inputs are going to be
wrong because, well, it's essentially a
program that does all the tracking for
you. But yeah, that kind